Hi, this video explains how to profile
customers and prospects on your website
to give them a great and tailored trial
and onboarding experience. It's a clip
from a launch event video for 2023
release week two, but it's equally
relevant today.
Let's turn it over to Søren who tells me
more about it.
To show this in a more schematic way,
what happens is
you have your questionnaire on your
website, the prospects fills in the
answers depending on what kind of
questions that you ask them, they click
a button,
they're redirected to the standard trial
sign up at dynamics.com.
We then spin up the standard trial
and then we add the app that you have
told us to add.
We then store the information from the
questionnaire, the answers in a system
table inside Business Central and you
can use those before the sign-in happens
to pivot, add more things to the
experience based on what those answers
are.
This is a really great way to make it
customer-centric.
So, end of the day, from a user
perspective, what they see, they sign up
and they see an experience. They don't
see that anything else has been added,
they just see it as one coherent
experience that has your special sauce
in it.
So, here you see a website. This is my
partner website.
Actually, this is just a power app that
I quickly made to show this,
but it will represent a website. So,
here I want to ask new prospects to find
my website some questions because I want
to give them the right experience from
from day one. So, I ask them about what
they're interested in doing with
Business Central, I ask them about what
system they're currently using, and I
ask them about their company size, how
many do you think will be using Business
Central. And in this case, uh the the
prospect selects uh they're interested
in biodiversity and luckily we We a
solution just for that, for tracking
biodiversity progress.
They also said that they're interested
in Excel, or that they come from Excel,
sorry. Uh they're used to working with
Excel, and there are 10 to 20 of users
that use Business Central. So, we can
see why that they've grown out of using
that Excel spreadsheet.
Now, what happens here when they start
to trial is that I need to construct the
right information to pass along to
Business Central in order for Business
Central to spin up the right
at the right solution.
It means that the combination of these
choices imply a collection of onboarding
elements, checklist tasks, banner, role
center, what have you, in a coherent
experience that that's bundled together
in an AppSource app. And I want to load
that app. So, when they have chosen
these specific things, I might want to
load my solution A.
But had they chosen, for example, these
three things, I wanted to load solution
B.
And so on. And you will be the one who
can decide for your company which
solutions do we want to load.
So, I click the start trial button as a
prospect, I I'm directed to the normal
sign-up process, where I sign in to my
tenant or sign up to a new tenant.
And then, the important part here is
that all of that context, where you came
from, the outcome of the questionnaire,
is passed along to Business Central in
this case.
So, now we load Business Central, we
create the environment with the standard
trial on top, but we add your special
sauce, we add your AppSource app and its
dependencies.
And now is the point where your app is
ready to say, "Oh, they chose Excel as
the previous system that they come
from."
Hey, I might want to load a checklist
item that describes why BC is great for
Excel users. That kind of thinking.
So, let's see how that plays out. So,
let's actually go and see see that app.
I landed in Business Central after going
through the sign-up and asking or
answering some some questions. And I
already see a product here that is much
more relevant than the standard trial. I
see that it has my name on it, so I feel
welcome. I also see that it's loaded
with an app called biodiversity
management. So, already now, this just
speaks my language. It speaks to my
expectations.
So, and I see there's a clear call to
action here. I'm I landed here in an
evaluation company, and what I what
we're about to show you here are some
examples of what you can do in terms of
onboarding. So, we're going to talk
through some of the onboarding elements
in this checklist. This checklist is not
intended to be the great checklist for
you to onboard a customer, but it's
intended to give you inspiration to what
kind of elements can you use here. So,
first of all, use a video. In this case,
I know that this prospect was interested
in biodiversity. So, I want to play them
a video that will tell them maybe a
snack-sized video that will tell them
exactly why BC plus this biodiversity
management app is just fantastic for
their business.
Let's assume that we watched that video
for now. We just we skip this.
Maybe you also want to guide them
through setup.
And for some kinds of modules, for some
kind of solutions, the checklist itself
is not,
you know, really geared to handle many
setup elements. We should really strive
to have a fairly short checklist. So,
what we can do is actually we can spin
off, we can branch off the checklist,
and run, let's say, a sub checklist
here. So, what you saw me doing here was
actually call the assisted setup list
page, but it's filtered now only to
contain my setup elements. And that's a
great way to say, "Hey, here are just a
number of steps you need to go through
to have this module set up."
In this case, I just want to show you an
example of calling one of these. So,
here I have an assisted setup that says
for this biodiversity solution, I need
to import some plants. So,
now it's plants. It could be the chart
of accounts. It could be posting groups.
It could be whatever you want to import
in terms of data as an alternative to
using configuration packages.
So, this case, and you can see I've even
branded this assisted setup.
I want to import a list of plants from
GitHub. So, I know that I have a JSON
file with plants that I open source on
GitHub because I want the community to
contribute to this list of plants.
I click next.
And now we see it's actually now listed
in sort of a temporary state. So, when I
click next, they will actually be
imported. This is just a way for me to
sort of validate that it looks fine. I
This is This is the list that I expect
to to import.
So, we'll do that.
And we'll click finish. So, you see how
using an assisted setup
I could even ask more questions here to
clarify which data do I want to load.
So, you can imagine if a customer is not
using doing projects, for example, just
leave those accounts out of the chart of
accounts or something else where you
don't want to load data that is not
used. So, think about loading data in a
just-in-time fashion this way.
So, let's just close this one and say
that we we did this kind of setup for
now.
Now, the user also said, "We use Excel
today."
I want to speak to that because we have
some very cool Excel integrations. So,
what I want to do is I want to
open a page on that plant data that I
just imported, and I want to show a
great spotlight tour that that spotlight
the Excel integration capabilities.
So, I call the spotlight tour here. I
can You as a partner can modify this
text, of course, and say, "Why is this
great on this entity to use edit in
Excel?"
So, I call out Excel here and say, "Hey,
for example, you can edit this list of
plants in Excel and import it back into
BC." We're not going to do that right
now, but this is just a great way to
call out these standard integrations
like share to teams and edit in Excel.
Let me go back here to to the checklist.
Now,
we also added new things in this
release.
So, if I start now, and this is actually
is a report that I'm starting.
I wanted to provide a super cool report
out of the box that is based on Excel
layouts. I want them to see a nice graph
of all the plants they just imported.
The new thing here is you see the
teaching tip popping up for the request
page for the report request page
educating me about what can I expect
from this report? Why does it exist?
Uh maybe there could be some hints about
how to best filter it to get the best
experience with this report. But, in
this case, I just want to see that nice
looking report.
And what we'll see it it will open in in
Excel, and it shows me already the plant
occurrences last year. So, remember
we're tracking biodiversity. I want to
keep track of how often has this been
reported has been spotted in the wild.
So, I can see here my list of plants.
This is an Excel layout that I provide
with my app. So, the customer hasn't
even, you know, needed to do anything.
They don't need to do this. When we
print this Excel layout, uh or print
this report, we will update the data
set, and the graph will automatically
update. This is a super cool way to do
alternative reports for your for your
customers. And you can imagine all kinds
of uh complex or less complex Excel
layouts.
Let's mark that as complete as well.
Now, I can also, of course, manage my
plants. So, I can start that list of
plants at I as I had before.
And one extra cool thing that we added
in this release, you already know the
teaching tips. You know that you can add
markdown Uh to do bold and italics
inside teaching tips and we can also
link. So here we link to the insects
page. We haven't tracked any insects
yet.
But I want to take the tour. And here it
says I can analyze my top plants. And
basically what this does, it opens a
query
in analysis mode
saying that hey, here's some great data
for you. And now we have a teaching tip
that educates the user about what is
this analysis all about? What is it that
you're seeing here? Because now this is
fairly simple and I can see that it's
sorted by number of occurrences, but it
could be a more complex thing. So it
could be great that I would be educated
about this. And of course, in this
release, as I'm sure you'll see,
uh now you can for example duplicate it
to give it another name.
Uh let me just call it test. And you can
copy a link to this specific analysis
and send this to a colleague, send it in
Teams, and when they open it, they'll go
directly into this analysis because
you've just spent a weekend doing it and
uh it's just a perfect analysis. So use
teaching tips to educate users about
what are they seeing here.
All right, let's go back here.
And let's actually go back to the
checklist.
So
let's skip this for now.
Finally, in my example here, I actually
want the user to go to my website
because we have the perfect place for
them to land after they've gone through
the experience, where we can take them a
step further. But you could also imagine
you could take them into my company,
start setting things up for real,
uh add the data,
add more videos that guide them through
processes, and then go live.
So
this was just one way to sort of stitch
together some onboarding pieces. You get
the idea with all these elements. It's
up to you to think about you can stitch
them together. Now, the great thing
about what you just saw here is that
this app that I loaded here is available
on GitHub. It's the onboarding sample
app, and you can go fork it today and
use that as a template to hit the ground
running for your onboarding experiences.
So, that you will know which events do
you have to subscribe to, where do you
do this, and where do you do that.
Let's just go through the most important
ones now.
So,
what was actually customer-centric to
this experience that you just saw?
Well, first of all, we loaded a customer
role center.
There's a few things that's important
for doing that. So, we loaded a customer
role center, we attached it to a role,
and we set that role for the current
user before they signed in. So, you see
here the events that that are necessary
to subscribe to to make that happen. You
can also see that in the in the code of
the sample app.
We also changed the welcome banner text,
and again, to Sarah's point before, it's
just super important to greet them with
the most relevant uh text and greeting
once you see the product. It literally
is the first thing that you see.
And you see here which event you need to
subscribe to to do that.
And speaking about relevance,
it's really is the checklist tasks that
are uh you know, doing the work. The The
This is your stage to lead the customer
through
uh that first experience. What is it you
think they should get excited about?
This is where you can do even pre-sale
stuff. If they spin up uh spin up a new
trial, you can use this for of course
for the real onboarding scenario as
well, and you can do both. That really
is up to you.
Branch off checklists to do more
elaborate setups. You saw me uh
opening the assisted setup list filtered
to your custom category, and you do that
by calling the open assisted setup
function in the guide experience item.
And what we talked about before about
using assist setups to ask more
questions, to clarify which data do you
have to load here? In my example, I just
loaded the plants. It could be that I
wanted to ask the user about, "Hey, are
you interested in trees or flowers
only?" And then only load that data. You
get the idea for your data.
Consider open-sourcing that data. If you
have data that you build but many others
also build, would it make sense to pull
your resources and and open-source it?
Could be.
GitHub is a great source for those kind
of things.
Again, call out the spotlight tours.
Shine a big bright spotlight on those
core integrations, Excel and Teams for
your custom entities. It's a great way
to generate some excitement. And one of
the reasons we hear customers investing
in Business Central is the whole
ecosystem of surrounding apps from
Microsoft.
Educate users with teaching tips on
reports. It's a great way to give them
some hints about what this list report
all about. Why should they care about
it? And how should they maybe
uh set some initial filters to get the
best outcome? And with other like with
other teaching tips, you can use the
about title and about text properties to
do that in AL.
Again, use Excel layouts. You can do
stunning layouts and provide the Excel
layout file out of the box with your
app, so the customer doesn't have to do
anything except but print the report.
There's some great examples and there's
more guidance at this
link. Check out the guidance there for
more samples and some tips and tricks.
And the final thing I want to call out
here is use teaching tips on query
objects as well.
It's It's a good experience to get some
guidance on, "Hey, what is this analysis
that I just just opened directly from
another page? What is it all about?"
To learn more, visit
aka.ms/bconboarding.
Thank you for watching.